You know, when I first saw the demos for
Google's new IDE product called
anti-gravity, I was genuinely excited.
Not hype train excited, but actually
interested because there are a few ideas
in there that looked like real progress
for what an agentic IDE could be. The
ability to manage multiple separate
projects with multiple agents working on
them all from a single centralized
window. That's something I've actually
wanted. And the review process where it
can automatically fire up Chrome and
record a screencast and check the agents
work. That's a genuinely clever approach
to verification. So, I cleared some time
this week and I gave anti-gravity a real
try. And I have to be honest with you,
what I found was dysfunctional. I almost
decided not to even publish this video
because I couldn't even complete the
demo that I had planned. But in the end,
I wanted you to see what I'm seeing,
both the good and the bad, because there
are some legitimately good ideas here
for pushing forward what an agentic IDE
should be. And I have to give the team
at Google credit for that. But if
[clears throat] I'm honest, I'm also
kind of surprised to see a product this
rough around the edges ship from a
company as large as Google. Not to
mention the fact that they forked VS
Code, a Microsoft project, to build it.
That's an interesting choice as well. So
today, you'll see my first look at
Google Anti-gravity. Who knows, maybe
some of these ideas might actually
stick. Maybe they'll fix the bugs and
this thing becomes actually usable. Or
maybe Cursor might take a few cues from
these genuinely good concepts here and
execute them in a way that actually
works. I want to hear what you think in
the comments. Now, before I dive in, if
you're new here, I'm Brian Castle. I
help professional developers stay ahead
of the curve when it comes to building
with AI. And every week, I send my
builder briefing. That's a free 5-minute
read to help you stay sharp. Get yours
by going to buildermethods.com.
And subscribers can get in on my live
workshops. This month, I'm covering my
AI first design process. So, you can
join me live or grab that recording if
it's already passed. Okay, let's get
into it. All right. So, let's fire up
anti-gravity and we'll see what we're
working with here. Now, when I open it
up, I'm looking at what they call the
editor view, which is very, very similar
to cursor and VS Code. As I said, it is
a fork of VS Code. But the other main
view is what they call their agent
manager. And I would say that between
these two views, the agent manager is
where Google Anti-gravity is really
trying to innovate and really push their
vision for what an agentic IDE should
be. And so really the whole point of
using anti-gravity would be to use it in
this view in in the agent manager
because my first impressions of the
editor view again are just exactly the
same as you know VS Code or cursor. Uh,
I'm not really seeing a whole lot that's
like different or a good reason to use
this view. And to be honest, I I really
do wish that this agent manager view and
the and the editor view were sort of
merged in the same window because as
I'll talk about here, I am pretty
interested in some of their ideas for
how an agentic IDE should be laid out
here in the agent view. Um, but I do
like how in cursor I could easily flip
between them in a single window. Now
before I get too deep into the unique
aspects of uh anti-gravity you know
since this is a VS code uh fork that
that means that you can import your
settings and your key bindings and your
extensions. So for example so if I open
up the user settings you know by default
when I when I just fire up anti-gravity
for the first time this is empty. So I
haven't customized any user settings
yet. But if I go over to cursor and I
open up the user settings there, which
you know, as you know, cursor is also a
VS Code fork. So I can grab all of my
user settings, this JSON, and just drop
it in here. And once I save that, it's
going to ask me to restart because, you
know, it changes the uh the layout a
little bit. So there we go. I mean, that
that changes some of the sizing, a
little bit of the colors, and I've got
some other settings in there. The other
thing that I'll want to do is get my key
bindings in there. So, I'll I'll go to
the keyboard shortcuts JSON. And I have
a bunch of custom key bindings that I've
set up in cursor and VS Code. Um, and
I'm going to drop these in my keyboard
shortcuts JSON in anti-gravity. And I'll
do that. So, now I have all my all of my
common keyboard shortcuts that I'm used
to from my days of working with VS Code
and cursor, which is my everyday IDE at
the moment. So, you know, like for me, I
like to use like command T to pop up the
the terminal, command L to open up the
chat, uh, commandB to open up my file
explorer, and I've got a whole bunch of
other key bindings that I use every
single day, all the time. And in fact, I
did an entire video about how I try to
stay fast and stay on the keyboard
without touching the mouse in cursor. I
did that a few months ago, so you can
check that out on my channel. All right,
so I've got my custom settings and my
key bindings imported into Google
Anti-gravity the way that I'm used to
having them from VS Code. So that's kind
of nice. But let's get into some of the
more unique features that anti-gravity
has to offer. And what I'm always trying
to look for when I'm evaluating a new
tool is how useful is this compared to
what I'm currently using. Now I would be
coming from cursor. So everything that I
evaluate here is going through the lens
of like is this actually better than
cursor for my particular workflow when
it comes to building products every day
using AI. So let's open up that agent
manager and I can do a command E to open
that up. And you know, one of the very
first things that popped out to me about
about anti-gravity that seems different
and maybe better, something that I'm I'm
really intrigued by is the idea of
having multiple workspaces here in the
sidebar. You know, I I work on several
different projects from, you know, from
day to day. I'm working on my builder
methods site every day. Of course, I've
got my personal site. I'm always
spinning up new apps and working on
things. So, it's really nice to have
different workspaces because when I am
using cursor, what I'm often doing is
just opening up, you know, multiple
cursor windows and throwing them across
my different uh desktops and flipping
around with different windows for each
individual workspace. I kind of like
that from a mental model because like
every project is completely separate
from a workspace standpoint, but I
really like the idea of at least trying
to consolidate all of my different
projects and different agents working on
different projects in a single sidebar
like this. So that's kind of
interesting. And here in this agent
manager, we have this, you know,
centralized chat, which is very similar
to the new cursor 2.0 uh agent view or
whatever they call that. here in the
dropown, I can open up any of the the
workspaces that I have opened over here.
And so that would sort of So if I want
to like flip over to my builder methods
project, I would do that. And now I'm
I'm going to kick off an agent with that
one. Or if I wanted to go to this uh
little demo app where I was listing out
baseball teams, I can do that. Now I'm
going to come back to interacting with
different workspaces and agents here in
just a sec. But one other new concept
that I really kind of like about what
anti-gravity is is proposing here is
this idea of the playground because this
really matches something that I do
almost every single day, which is
quickly spinning up new, often temporary
projects to use as demos or to test
something out, but not really a project
that's going to turn into something. Or
maybe it will. So rather than going
through the whole process of like
actually spinning up a whole new project
and creating a GitHub repo for it and
and creating a workspace for it, I can
just start coding. I can just start
hacking on something in the playground.
I can just hit that. And I was Let's go
ahead and have Gemini 3 spin up a simple
demo app. I'll use dictation for this.
Please spin up a front-end client side
only uh vit and react app. also use shad
CN components and Tailwind CSS. Let's
create a simple to-do list manager with
checkable check boxes and uh the ability
to add new items to the list. I know, I
know it's just a to-do list app. It's
super simple, kind of boring, nothing
exciting here. Uh but the purpose of
this video and this demo is really to
just kind of kick the tires on Google
Anti-gravity and see what these features
are all about. So, let's just get that
going. The other thing, by the way, is,
you know, Google is providing some token
usage for for Gemini 3 when you're using
Google Anti-gravity, but I have noticed
that just with a little bit of use
earlier today, I' I've already kind of
burned through that token limit and I
had to wait about an hour until I can
start using it again. So, that's why I'm
just going to try to keep it simple here
and keep it pretty light on on the agent
token usage. And that was just a simple
uh request. And I can see agent taking
unexpectedly long to load. All right.
What happens if I hit this button, open
editor? Okay. So that that takes me back
to, you know, the editor view and and
I'm still looking at this temporary, if
you will, uh, playground app, but I
don't really know what's happening. So,
you know, I' I've been running into a
lot of these little clunky UX issues
when I'm just trying to play around with
anti-gravity. Like I I I just got to be
honest. My first run experience
throughout today and yesterday playing
around with it just doesn't really click
too much. All right, let's try to get
this going. And you know, I can't even
seem to stop it either. I don't know.
Should we try the old quit it and reopen
it? Let's try that. All right, so I'm
going to go back to the playground. I'll
just try this again. I'm just going to
say hello. Is this thing on? Okay, so
after a little bit of a wait, it did
respond. So it it looks like we're we're
up and running. how you know and this is
clearly a bug because this little MLB
teams page was a test playground that I
started earlier and I had already moved
that into my workspaces but now it's
calling this new playground by the same
name which is confusing and doesn't seem
correct to me but we'll keep rolling
with it. Let's let's just try to get it
to actually spin up an app that I can
build something on. Spin up a client
side only app with Vit React Shad CN and
Tailwind CSS. Make it a simple to-do
list manager with checkable tasks and
titles for each task. And you know what?
Let's actually try out the planning mode
before we actually build that and take a
look at that. One thing I've noticed, I
don't know if it's just like today and
it's sort of high traffic, but Gemini 3
seems to be working even slower when I'm
running it in anti-gravity compared to
when I been when I've been using Gemini
3 in cursor. Yeah. No, this this totally
crapped out. Okay, here we go. I think
we are finally actually working. Let's
see how it does. Third times a charm
here. I mean, maybe it's because it's a
playground. Let's just try creating a
new workspace, I guess. All right. So,
uh, normally when I start up a new
project, I would use the terminal to do
that. Maybe to make a directory or to
clone a GitHub repo or something. Uh, in
this case, for a super simple demo, I
would want to open up a terminal and and
and make a new directory. Unfortunately,
in the agent manager view, I can't just
do that off the bat. So, if I try to hit
uh command J, which is supposed to open
the terminal, I can't do that. And I
think because we can't actually open up
a terminal until I'm already in a
conversation, like an active
conversation with an agent. Um, which is
kind of baffling if you ask me. So, for
example, if I'm in here, so this was
something that I worked on earlier. I I
added a feature to my builder methods
app. Since I already have an an active
conversation going in one of my
workspaces, I can open up the terminal
now. And of course I'm of course it it
assumes that I'm in my builder methods
directory. So you know here I I would be
able to you know cd out of it. But again
just like in terms of like context.
Okay. I like I like the idea of being
able to flip between multiple workspaces
and even conceptually the idea of having
a playground all in one all all in one
window here. But if it requires actually
like talking to an agent before I'm even
able to open up a terminal and you know
either start up a new folder or change
the the git branch that I'm on. That
just doesn't really make any sense to
me. You know, of course I could just
like get go back to the editor view and
again I'm still in one of my workspaces.
I'm not in my like general agent manager
view here. So just the the context and
the management of these different
windows, you know, like we still have
multiple windows happening. So, it sort
of defeats the purpose of having this
one centralized uh manager. Anyway,
let's let's at least try to get
something going here, right? So, I'm
going to uh sort of CD to my to my temp
folder and I will Okay, so I've just
created a folder and now let's open up a
workspace for that. Okay, here is demo
app. Now, we're in an actual workspace.
I would have liked to start this off as
a playground and then convert it to a
workspace, but that just didn't work
here. So, I'm going to go ahead and
create a demo app. And again, like I
can't even open up the terminal here
until I start talking to it. So, let's
just try this one more time. And let's
do that in planning mode and and we'll
see it create a plan. Okay. So now that
I'm talking to it, now I would actually
have the ability to open up the terminal
and if I if I had git initialized, I
could, you know, change branches if I
wanted to, which again, like that
workflow just doesn't really work for me
cuz I would want to change the or or
start a new branch before I have the
agent working on something. But the way
that anti-gravity is set up, I can't
actually open up the terminal and create
a new branch until the agent has already
started working on something. Very
strange. Okay, so it looks like it has
started to create the implementation
plan. One other concept that I do like
about Google Anti-gravity is this idea
of artifacts. If I so I could pull open
this sidebar here and this is a really
interesting concept for an agentic IDE
and cursor doesn't really have something
quite like this where you know we have
these artifacts like the like planning
and there and sometimes when we get into
the review stage there are like media
videos or pl of like browser recordings
or browser screenshots those would show
up as artifacts. So I do like the idea
of having these like planning documents
and review documents as well as like a
list of file changes having that
separate from my files explorer. You
know, typically in cursor I would be
saving plans or saving specs as markdown
files in the codebase itself, but I do
like the idea of having them like
visually separated into this into this
artifacts sidebar. So that's a really
cool idea. I kind of wish that cursor
would pick pick that up. Now, something
that's also interesting, like I thought
I was still in planning mode, but it
appears to have just gone ahead and
started uh implementing the app, which
is which is fine, but that's not what I
expected from a user experience. So, you
know, like there are just a lot of rough
edges, and I'm pretty surprised to to
see that kind of thing from a huge
company like Google, to be totally
honest. Again, one of the unique ideas
that anti-gravity is bringing to the
table here is the idea of being able to
comment on, you know, highlighting
individual lines and leaving a comment
and bringing that comment into your
conversation with the agent. Again,
that's something I haven't really seen.
Um, you know, cursor does have the
ability to sort of like highlight and
and do some like inline agent coding,
but this is this is more of a
conversation with your agent and it
makes it really easy to reference
specific details that might be off or
need some course correction in your
plan. And hopefully later I can get to a
point where where I have a visual review
thing that I can comment on as well if
we ever get there. I'm going to accept
this. I would have liked that to be a
little bit more like alert like this is
waiting for my attention. All right, so
it's still working on this. It's been
several minutes and again I did a
version of this demo using cursor
earlier today sort of in prep for this
and it handled spinning up a simple app
like this in a matter of minutes. Even
using Gemini 3, it it just seems to be
just moving a lot slower when I'm using
anti-gravity. One thing I do like about
the feed here is that the the interface
seems a little bit more intuitive. I
like how these are like collapsible and
they and they and they and they animate
a little bit. I've got this little arrow
here. So, that that does make it a
little bit easier for me to like
visually scan what's going on compared
to some of the other tools where I'm
just seeing a feed of text fly by and I
and it's sort of hard to to get a read
on what's happening. And you know what?
Going back to the issue with the agent
just go going ahead with the proceeding
of of of doing the plan. I do see this
setting up here. Oh, I just lost it. Oh,
yeah. Over here, agent decides. looks
like always proceed agent decides or
request review. So I thought that that
would that would relate to just like
asking my permission to you know install
things or run commands. I didn't know
that this would also result in making a
plan and then having the agent proceed
to building that plan. Um that again
that just seemed like a little off to me
compared to what what the normal
workflow I think should be when we're
talking about spec driven development,
right? I want to think about the spec,
make a plan, think about the plan,
review the plan, and then I want to be
the one to say go. Um, and so even if
I'm giving it permission to run commands
and stuff, I still want to be the one to
initiate like, yes, we're going to go
ahead and build this now. And I would
say at this point, like it's been almost
10 minutes of of waiting for it to spin
up an extremely simple demo application,
a to-do list app. Oh, okay. So, here's
where, you know, the interface kind of
got in its own way. Like, something was
like this is waiting for me to accept,
but I didn't even see that because it
was tucked away. See, it was tucked away
inside of this expand thing. I And I
only happened to notice that one step
requires user input. I mean, that should
be alerting me in my face. That's saying
that's saying like this is not making
progress until you open this up and
click expand. I don't know. I'm trying
to stay positive. Trying to find the
positive in in this. Let's see if I can
make this always. I'll say always
proceed. I'll accept that one and maybe
that'll make the future requests just go
through. Oh, [laughter] I hit the limit.
We haven't even finished. Oh, man. You
know, speaking of selecting models, this
is almost a dealbreaker. I say I would
say it is a dealbreaker for me. It's
just the lack of selection here with the
models. Obviously, Google is going to
give us Gemini 3 Pro as as an option. Uh
they do have Claude Sonnet 4.5, but they
don't have Claude Opus 4.5, and I I have
a Claude Pro account and and I would be
able I would like to be able to use that
in my IDE, but apparently that's not an
option. I do sometimes use GPT5, but
that's also not available here. And I
did go into the settings to try to see
if like in cursor where you know you can
add and remove all sorts of different
models um that we don't seem to have
that option here in in in Google
Anti-gravity at least not right now. So,
you know, pretty limited. But let's see
if we can actually get this simple demo
app up and running. Hopefully by the end
of this video, let's see if we can have
Claude Sonnet 4.5 pick up the pieces
here. I'll just say continue. Now again,
I did set it on always proceed, but it's
still asking me for permission to to to
run some things. So, okay. Okay. So, so
Anti-gravity has [clears throat]
launched its Chrome browser, and you can
see the uh the the blue glow around it.
Of course, I'm looking at an error. It's
not actually the the simple app is just
not actually working yet. Let's see if
it can work through the issues that it's
that it's finding there. But this
browser is being controlled by uh I
guess this is sonnet 4.5 through
anti-gravity. Okay. So this just looks
like a complete fail if you ask me. It
it g it says that it it's complete. I
see we have a walk through and this is
what features supposedly were
implemented and it gave me a screenshot
of it not working. I mean what what are
we talking about here? So, I mean, what
if I just run this myself?
Whoa. Okay. I thought the same I thought
clicking that would Wow.
I can't clear. Okay, that's not even
clearing the terminal. Let's at least
try to get it working.
What is this? That [laughter] That is
not a Tailwind class. So, I don't know
what's happening there. Um, of course it
seems to be using Tailwind 3, not
Tailwind 4. Okay, so now we're up and
running. I would have liked to to show
the actual review process that
anti-gravity offers. That was one of the
things that I was most excited about
when I when I watched the uh the preview
videos for anti-gravity was the fact
that it should be able to open up your
app and use it and record its own
screencast to to review and and and you
know show that it's working in this
case. It tried to do that but it clearly
was not working. Um and yeah, so now one
more aspect of of this agent manager
view which again I I like I like it in
concept. I like the idea of being able
to have access to all my workspaces and
be able to flip between them, which is
something I actually do in my in my
workflow day-to-day. But I do often want
to see the actual files, right? I want
to see I want to be able to pull open a
file and either edit code myself or at
least just review how the code and how
the project is organized even if I'm not
the one coding it. Right? So if I'm here
in agent manager view instead of opening
up separate window like I I could open
up this this demo app I can click open
editor and that's going to open up the
traditional VS codebased editor here but
that is already a separate window and
that sort of defeats the purpose of
having a singular window to manage
multiple workspaces. Oh, my question is,
can I actually open up files and look at
look at my project files while I'm
looking at the uh agent view or the
agent manager? Um, the answer seems to
be sort of. I can, you know, I can open
up single single files here. Um, so, you
know, I can use the search if I if I
know the name of the file, I can I can
find it and then open it up and then,
you know, I can look through it. And
again, we have that really nice
commenting interface. So, that's really
cool. What I'm missing is the file
explorer. You know, if I go back to the
actual code editor here, I could
actually see my project. I can see the
folders. And even though I might not
click through this very often, I do
often look at it to see the structure
and also to like find a lot of times I'm
looking for sections of code that I
don't even know what the file is named
and I just have to sort of like visually
look for it. Um, and I it's it's nice to
know that I can open up single files,
but I still want to be able to just look
at my at my file exp I still just want
to be able to look at my file explorer
when I'm in this agent manager view, if
you will. So, that's Google
anti-gravity. And look, I wanted to like
this. The ideas here are genuinely good
ones. multi-RO management, multiple
agents in one window, that screen
recording review process. These are real
innovations that push forward what an
agentic IDE should be. But ideas only
matter if the execution is there. And
right now, it's just not. Maybe they'll
ship fixes and this thing becomes
something worth using. And I hope that
they do. But if you're looking for an
agentic IDE that actually works today,
the one that I use as my daily driver,
then you need to see what the team at
Cursor just shipped with their 2.0
version. It's a much better take on an
AI first code editor. And I did a full
review of Cursor 2.0 and the features
that I'm actually using in my daily
workflow. So, right after you hit
subscribe on this channel, I'll see you
over there next. Let's keep building.